Guide to the Norman Mosley Penzer Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Norman Mosley Penzer Papers,
1919-1928
Penzer, N. M. (Norman Mosley), 1892-1960.
160 items (4 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079208
Biographical Note
Editor. Penzer edited and annotated C.H. Tawney's translation of The Ocean of Story; Somadeva's Katha Sarit Sagara (1924-1928), in ten volumes, a group of ancient Indian folklore tales.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, notes, reviews, clippings, and pamphlets relating to C.H. Tawney's translation of The Ocean of Story and proofs of Penzer's annotations.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 2 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
Subjects
Tawney, C. H. (Charles Henry), 1838-1922.; Somadeva Bhaṭṭa, 11th cent.--Kathāsaritsāgara.--English.; Folklore--India.; Indic literature--Translations into English.; Editors.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-4. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1976 M-76 Saffron, Morris H. Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  Cataloged correspondence and manuscripts are interfiled
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 19 Dec 1923, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 20 Jan 1925, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 15 March 1925, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 28 June 1925, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 27 Nov 1925, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 4 June 1926, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 21 June 1926, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 6 Oct 1926, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bloomfield, Maurice To Norman Mosley Penzer, Baltimore, 31 Oct 1926, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cordier, Henri To [Norman Mosley Penzer], Paris, 11 Feb 1925, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Curzon, George Nathaniel Curzon, Marquess To [Norman Mosley Penzer], [London], 29 July 1924, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Edgerton, Franklin To Norman Mosley Penzer, New Haven, CT, 26 April 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Gaster, Moses To Norman Mosley Penzer, [London], 21 May 1925, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham To Norman Mosley Penzer, Rathfarnham, [UK], 6 Aug 1924, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham To Norman Mosley Penzer, Rathfarnham, [UK], 1 Jan 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham To Norman Mosley Penzer, Rathfarnham, [UK], 12 Jan 1927, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham To Norman Mosley Penzer, Rathfarnham, [UK], 16 Feb 1927, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham To Norman Mosley Penzer, Rathfarnham, [UK], 15 Feb 1928, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Halliday, William Reginald To Norman Mosley Penzer, London, 6 April 1928, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Macdonald, Duncan Black To Norman Mosley Penzer, Hartford, CT, 22 May 1933, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Macdonald, Duncan Black To Norman Mosley Penzer, Hartford, CT, 21 Sept 1933, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Rose, Horace Arthur To [Norman Mosley Penzer], St Brelade (?), Jersey, [UK], 1 July 1924, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Rouse, William Henry Denham To [Norman Mosley Penzer], Cambridge, [UK], 14 April 1924, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Stein, (Sir) Mark Aurel To [Norman Mosley Penzer], Srinagar, [India], 12 Nov 1923, (2 pages a.l.s. (with copy of reply) (Box 1)
  - Stein, (Sir) Mark Aurel To Norman Mosley Penzer, Srinagar, [India], 29 Dec 1923, (2 pages t.l.s. (with copy of reply) (Box 1)
  - Stein, (Sir) Mark Aurel To Norman Mosley Penzer, Oxford, 6 July 1924, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Stein, (Sir) Mark Aurel To Norman Mosley Penzer, Srinagar, [India], 18 July 1926, (2 pages t.l.s. (with copy of related letter) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, A. To Norman Mosley Penzer, Camberley, [UK], 5 Jan 1928, (6 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 28 July 1919, (1 page a.l.s. (with copy of related letter) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 4 Aug 1919, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 5 Jan 1920, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 23 Jan 1920, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 20 Aug 1920, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Tawney, Charles Henry To Norman Mosley Penzer, Chartley, [UK], 28 Aug 1920, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Temple, (Sir) Richard Carnac To Norman Mosley Penzer, Montreaux, Switzerland, 3 March 1924, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Temple, (Sir) Richard Carnac To Norman Mosley Penzer, Thonon le Bains, France, 2 Aug 1926, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Temple, (Sir) Richard Carnac To Norman Mosley Penzer, Montreaux, Switzerland, 12 March 1928, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Grierson, (Sir) George Abraham Foreword [to Vol. II of The Ocean of Story, edited by N.M. Penzer], Camberly, [UK], 2 Sept 1924, (15 pages t.ms.s. (with corrections in his hand) (Box 1)
  - Temple, (Sir) Richard Carnac Foreword [to Vol. I of The Ocean of Story, edited by N.M. Penzer], [Montreaux, Switzerland], [March 1924], (23 pages a.ms.) (Box 1)
  - The Ocean of Story. Manuscript pages and misc., () (Box 2)
  - The Ocean of Story. Prospectus, () (Box 2)
  - The Ocean of Story. Reviews, () (Box 2)
  - The Ocean of Story. Printed Misc., () (Box 2)
  - The Ocean of Story. Proofs: vol. 1-7, () (Box 3)
  - The Ocean of Story. Proofs: vol. 8-10, () (Box 4)